Julius Hobson Papers 001
People's Archive, MLK Library
- Series 1: CORE, 1961-1964
  The series documents Hobson's work in CORE in the early 1960s. It contains correspondence, memoranda, minutes, financial information, bulletins, CORE's constitution, and membership lists. It also contains information about the controversy over Hobson's expulsion from CORE, and campaigns against police brutality, employment discrimination, and inequality in D.C. public schools.
  - Correspondence, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Memoranda, Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Minutes, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Conventions, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Financial Receipts, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Constitution, 1962-1964 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Membership Lists, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Bulletins (Benjamin Franklin University), 1963 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous Papers, 1962-1964 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous Papers, 1962-1964 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Printed material, Undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Series 2: Associated Community Teams (ACT), 1964-1969
  The series primarily covers Hobson's work as Chairman of ACT in the early 1960s. It includes correspondence, newsletters, editorials, press releases, and internal memoranda regarding ACT's protests against police brutality and pupil tracking practices in D.C. The series also documents Hobson's involvement with the Black United Front (BU) and his rising support of black power in the mid-1960s. Included are BU's minute meetings, a typewritten list of the names and circumstances surrounding Black Panthers killed in Watts, and resolutions from the "National Conference on Black Power" in 1968. Significant names mentioned include Stokely Carmichael (Chair of the Black United Front), Elijah Muhammed, Adam Clayton Powell, H. Rap Brown, Chuck Stone, Sterling Tucker, and David Eaton.
  - Correspondence, 1964-1969 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1964-1969 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1964-1969 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1964-1969 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1964-1969 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1964-1969 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Media Editorials, 1965-1966 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous Papers, 1965-1971 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Black Power, 1965-1966 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Police, 1960-1968 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Hobson Testimony and interviews, 1965-1967 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Brief Analysis of Nixon Crime Bill, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Memoranda, 1964-1967 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Minutes, 1965-1966 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Newsletters, Undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Black United Front, 1968-1969 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Commission on Negro History and Culture Testimony, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Bankruptcy: "Debtor's Remedies Manual," ca. 1967 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Bankruptcy: "Freedom From Debt Through Bankruptcy", 1965-1968 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Bankruptcy: miscellaneous, 1964-1968 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Series 3: Hobson v. Hansen, 1965-1977
  The series primarily contains court documents in the Hobson v. Hansen case, originally filed in 1966, which challenged pupil tracking and expenditure inequities in D.C. public schools. Significant persons mentioned include attorney William Kunstler, plaintiffs' attorney, and Judge Skelly Wright who ordered the D.C. school system to end de facto segregation in 1967. Court papers include court decisions, exhibits, depositions, interrogatories, and various motions in the U.S. District Court and U.S. Court of Appeals for D.C. The series also contains statistics gathered by Hobson to support the litigation, correspondence among parties involved in the case, reports, clippings, newsletters, and press releases.
  - Correspondence, 1970-1977 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1970-1977 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1970-1977 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1966-1969 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1966-1969 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1966-1969 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1966-1969 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Court Documents, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Court Documents, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Court Documents, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Court Documents, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Court Documents, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Court Documents, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Court Documents, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Court Documents, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Court Documents, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Court Documents, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Plaintiff Exhibits, 1964-1966 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Appellate, 1967 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Hansen Appeal, 1967-1968 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Three Judge Court Appeal, 1967-1968 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Court of Appeal file, 1966-1968 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Motion to Intervene Court of Appeals, 1962-1968 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Hobson v. Hansen, 1965-1966 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - DC School Library Resources, 1965-1977 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Statistical Information, 1962-1974 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Statistical Information, 1962-1974 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Statistical Information, 1962-1974 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Episcopal Church Grant, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Post-Decretal, 1965-1970 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Chart G, 1969 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Misc. Notes, 1951 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Board of Education Response to Decision, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Supreme Court, 1966-1967 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - An Evaluation of Hobson v. Hanson National Capital Area Civil Liberties Defense and Educational Fund, 1968 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous reports, 1969-1971 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Announcement, 1967-1971 (Box 13, Folder 4)
- Series 4: Board of Education, 1963-1971
  The series includes correspondence, meeting minutes, memoranda, clippings, reports, proposals, and press releases which document Hobson's tenure on the D.C. Board of Education and his general interest in education.
  - Correspondence, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1969 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous, 1969 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Hobson v. Hewlett, 1967-1969 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Passing and Failing Marks received by Junior and Senior High School, 1959-1969 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Student rights, 1968 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Black history culture studies - Swahli, 1968-1970 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Unions, 1963-1969 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Campaign literature, 1968 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Miller teacher supportive evidence, 1968-1970 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - School data-teacher assignment and library curriculum, 1969 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - News releases and newsletters, 1969-1972 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Programs, 1968-1970 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Clippings, 1967-1971 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Memoranda, 1968-1970 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Meetings, 1969-1970 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Statements to Board, 1967-1969 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Statistical information, 1968-1971 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Reports and proposals, 1952-1971 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Reports and proposals, 1952-1971 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Reports and proposals, 1952-1971 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Reports and proposals, 1952-1971 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Hobson v. Hansen‑Decision and Reaction, 1950‑1968 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Hobson v. Hansen‑Decision and Reaction, 1950‑1968 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - School Board Tuition Grant Clark Plan, 1969-1973 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - School Board Tuition Grant Clark Plan, 1969-1973 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous, 1963-1971 (Box 20, Folder 5)
- Series 5: Washington Institute for Quality Education (WIQE), 1968-1972
  The series contains correspondence, memoranda, meeting minutes, membership lists, an organizational manual, bylaws, and financial records of the WIQE. It also contains various publications of the Institute, including The Damned Children published in 1970 that provided extensive quantitative data and tables about the education of poor and black children in D.C. public schools.
  - Correspondence, 1967-1970 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1967-1970 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Clippings, 1966-1967 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1971-1973 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1971-1973 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1971-1973 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Memoranda, 1968-1975 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Manual of Organization, 1968 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Chronological Files, Undated (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Chronological Files, Undated (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Chronological Files, Undated (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Chronological Files, Undated (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Bylaws, 1968 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Extracts from Minutes Book, 1969 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous, 1968-1974 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous, 1968-1974 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Statements and Testimonies, 1968-1971 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Articles, 1967-1974 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Proposals, 1968-1973 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Proposals, 1968-1973 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Hugh J. Scott Transfer Controversy, 1972 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - The Damned Children, 1970 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Publication Draft Material, 1960-1971 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Financial Records, 1969-1971 (Box 25, Folder 3)
- Series 6: Federal Job Discrimination, 1963-1978
  The series documents Hobson's efforts to end federal job discrimination through the courts in the Hobson v. Hampton case and through Congress. It consists mostly of correspondence to Hobson from a number of federal employees who experienced job discrimination and offered their general support and/or to act as plaintiffs in lawsuits. It also includes correspondence and court pleadings from many supportive organizations such as labor unions, the NAACP, and lawyers handling federal job discrimination cases. Employee files and correspondence among officials at the U.S. Civil Service Commission, other federal agency staff, Congress, and employee complainants provide excellent documentation on instances of job discrimination. Of particular significance are letters, individual petitions to Congress, congressional testimony, and legislation relating to hearings on federal job discrimination brought by Congressmen William Ryan and Charles Diggs in 1970. Also of significance are background for, and a copy of, Hobson's article Uncle Sam is a Bigot, which appeared in the Saturday Evening Post in 1968.
  - Correspondence, 1968-1973 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1968-1973 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1968-1973 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1968-1973 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1968-1973 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1968-1973 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, Undated (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Uncle Sam Is A Bigot, Undated (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Chairman Macy, 1967-1972 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - J.W.H. Statements, 1968-1969 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Fact Sheets, 1968 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Papers, 1968-1972 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous Papers, 1968-1972 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1963-1970 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Scrapbook‑‑Critical Letters of Uncle Sam Is A Bigot, 1968 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook--Individual Complaints, 1964-1968 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Scrapbook- Pursued Cases, Undated (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Scrapbook- Pursued Cases, Undated (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Hobson v. Robert E. Hampton, 1969 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Complaints for Injunctive and Declaratory Relief, July 1969 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Affidavit Files, 1970-1971 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Court Documents Filed, 1969 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Plaintiff's Authorization Form‑‑Congressman William F. Ryan, 1968-1969 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Hobson v. Hampton, 1969 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Petitions from Federal Employees Protesting Job Discrimination, 1968 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Discrimination in Federal Employment‑‑Authorization of Hobson to Represent, 1968-1978 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Court Documents, 1968 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Court Documents, 1968 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Congressional File, 1969-1970 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Memoranda, 1968-1971 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Statistical Information, 1968-1970 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Cases by Precedent by State, 1967-1969 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous Papers, 1965-1970 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous Papers, 1965-1970 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Joseph T. Watkins and District Government Discrimination, 1968-1978 (Box 32, Folder 2)
- Series 7: Statehood Party/Home Rule, 1970-1976
  The series contains correspondence, memoranda, meeting minutes, court documents and clippings that document Hobson's involvement in the founding of the Statehood Party and efforts to bring home rule to the District. In particular, it contains pleadings filed by Hobson and other members of the Statehood Party challenging the constitutionality of D.C. elections laws as well as the Hobson v. Tobriner case filed in 1966 challenging the constitutionality of the commissioner-form of government. It also includes speeches, flyers, press releases, clippings, legislation and legal research supporting both home rule and statehood in the District.
  - Correspondence, 1971 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Memoranda, 1970-1971 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Local Community Press, 1971 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous, 1972 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Court Documents, 1966-1976 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Home Rule Miscellaneous Papers, 1970-1976 (Box 34, Folder 3)
- Series 8: Fair Housing/Transportation Campaigns, 1965-1972
  The series documents efforts by Hobson and other civil rights leaders to end racial discrimination in the provision of housing and transportation services for District residents IT covers his efforts while at CORE to organize a bus boycott and to picket and lobby for a fair housing law. It includes press releases, political flyers, court documents, correspondence, and clippings.
  - Open (Fair) Housing, 1969 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Transportation‑‑ Case Material‑‑DC Transit, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Transportation, 1965-1971 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Report, 1969-1970 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous Papers, 1965-1971 (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous Papers, 1965-1971 (Box 35, Folder 6)
- Series 9: Media Fairness Campaign, 1969-1972
  The series includes correspondence, a community media survey, reports, and court/FCC filings, which opposed the renewal of WMAL-TV's FCC license in 1969. The leading plaintiff Chuck Stone and others complained that WMAL, owned by the Evening Star Broadcasting Company, did not serve the public interest because the station did not adequately address the needs of the African-American community.
  - Correspondence, 1969-1972 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - FCC Documents‑‑DC Media Companies, 1969-1972 (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Papers, 1969 (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Papers, 1969 (Box 36, Folder 4)
- Series 10: Peoples Party/Peace and Anti-War Movement, 1967-1973
  The series contains correspondence among Hobson and individuals and organizations involved with the movement to stop to the Viet Nam War. It also contains clippings, a campaign bumper sticker, press releases, flyers, correspondence, campaign literature, congressional testimony, government documents, and party platforms in connection with the Peace Party's 1972 Presidential campaign and efforts to stop the War. In 1972, Julius Hobson agreed to run as the Vice Presidential candidate on the ticket with Presidential candidate Dr. Benjamin Spock. Of particular significance, is correspondence among Hobson, activists at the New Mobilization Committee to End the War in Vietnam, and members of the Black United Front, a D.C.-based black power organization, regarding the Committee's efforts to coordinate plans for anti-war demonstrations in Washington in the fall of 1969. Correspondents include Benjamin Spock, the Reverend Doug Moore (Chair of the Black United Front), Dave Dellinger and Stewart Meacham (National Co-Chair of the Committee to End the War).
  - Correspondence, 1967-1973 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Memoranda, 1969-1972 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Papers I, 1969-1972 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Papers I, 1969-1972 (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Hobson Court Petition, Undated (Box 37, Folder 5)
- Series 11: City Council Correspondence, 1974-1977
  The series consists of correspondence from Hobson's years as a City Council member and documents his work on the Council. The majority of the correspondence is arranged alphabetically by topic or name of correspondent. Thereafter, the remaining correspondence is arranged chronologically. Important correspondents include Congressman Ronald Dellums, Congressman Charles Diggs, Delegate Walter Fauntroy, and Mayor Walter Washington.
  - "A", 1975-1977 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Abramowitz, 1974-1975 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - "B", 1975 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - "C", 1975-1976 (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - "D", 1975-1977 (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Dellum, 1975 (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Diggs, 1973-1975 (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - "E", 1975-1977 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Events Attended, 1975 (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - "F", 1975-1976 (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Fauntroy, 1975 (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Federal City Club, 1974-1975 (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - "G", 1975-1976 (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - "H", 1975-1976 (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - Hobson Council Memoranda, 1975 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - "I", 1975-1976 (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - "J ", 1975-1976 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - "K", 1975-1976 (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - "L", 1975-1977 (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Massage Parlors, 1977 (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Mc, 1975-1976 (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - "N", 1975-1976 (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - News Release, 1975-1976 (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - "O", 1976 (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - "P", 1975-1976 (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Personnel, 1975 (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - "Q", 1975-1976 (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - "R", 1975-1976 (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - "S", 1975-1976 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Staff Memoranda, 1975 (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - "T", 1975-1976 (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Tirana, 1975 (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - "U", 1975 (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - "V", 1975-1976 (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - "W", 1975-1977 (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - Washington, 1975-1977 (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - "XYZ", 1975-1977 (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Chronological Files, January-December 1975 (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Chronological Files, 1976 (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Chronological Files, October 1976-March 1977 (Box 46, Folder 1)
- Series 12: Topical Files, 1973-1977
  The series consists of a variety of topical files from Hobson's years on the City Council. It includes correspondence, a council calendar (1975-76), constituent service records, legislation, and weekly reports of the Committee on Education, Recreation and Youth Affairs (1976-77). Topics covered include the Returnable Beverage Law, police surveillance, the Committee on Education, and contributors to his campaigns.
  - Committee on Education, 1975-1977 (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Committee on Education, 1975 (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1974-1977 (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Programs, 1976 (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - Statements, 1974-1976 (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - School Cost Center Reporting Resolution, 1976 (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - Returnable Beverage Container Law, 1975 (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - Resource Recovery Facility, 1975 (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - Police Surveillance, 1975 (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - Contributors to Campaign, 1973 (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - The Inaugural Event, 1977 (Box 48, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence Log, 1975-1976 (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - Constituent Service Records, 1975-1976 (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - Council Calendar, 1975-1976 (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - Certificates Hobson Awarded (Blank), Undated (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Letterhead Paper and Envelopes (Small), Undated (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Business Cards, Undated (Box 51, Folder 2)
- Series 13: Freedom of Information Privacy Act Request, 1969-1970; 1976-1977
  The series documents Hobson's efforts to obtain information under the Freedom of Information Act from the FBI, CIA, the D.C. Metropolitan Police Department, and other federal agencies. Hobson sought information under the Freedom of Information Act to discover whether and to what extent investigative agencies conducted surveillance of his activities as a civil rights and peace activist. Hobson's FOIA requests, correspondence, and the actual documents and reports produced in connection with the requests are found in the series. (See also Series 18: Biography for additional FOI files).
  - Julius W. Hobson's FOIA Request I and II, 1976 (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - Julius W. Hobson's FOIA Request I and II, 1976 (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - Freedom of Information Privacy Act Request I, 1976-1977 (Box 52, Folder 3)
  - Freedom of Information Privacy Act Request I, 1976-1977 (Box 52, Folder 4)
  - Hobson v. Wilson, 1976 (Box 53, Folder 1)
  - Tina C. Hobson, 1976 (Box 53, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Papers, 1969-1970 (Box 53, Folder 3)
- Series 14: Hobson v. Wilson, 1969-1983
  The series contains correspondence, clippings, court transcripts, exhibits, and court pleadings in connection with the Hobson v. Wilson case. The case was brought by the ACLU to seek damages for individuals who claimed that their civil rights were violated by illegal police and FBI surveillance in the 1960s.
  - American Civil Liberties Union Law Suit, 1976 (Box 53, Folder 1)
  - Hobson v. Wilson (82‑2160) Vol. I, 1982-1983 (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - Hobson v. Wilson (82‑2159) Vol. II, 1982-1983 (Box 54, Folder 2)
  - Research Motions N.O.V. and New Trial and Misc., 1977-1983 (Box 54, Folder 3)
  - Hobson v. Wilson (Post‑Trial Pleading Vol. I), 1981-1982 (Box 54, Folder 4)
  - Hobson v. Wilson (Post Trial Pleading Vol. II), 1982 (Box 54, Folder 5)
  - Hobson Attorney Fees Discovery, 1982 (Box 54, Folder 6)
  - Extra copies of pleading, 1982 (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - Hobson‑Temp. file (Trial), 1982 (Box 55, Folder 2)
  - Office Expenses, 1984 (Box 55, Folder 3)
  - Attorneys' Fees Application‑Work Sheets, 1981 (Box 55, Folder 4)
  - Research‑damages, 1983 (Box 55, Folder 5)
  - Research‑Injunction (with Reference Material), 1982 (Box 55, Folder 6)
  - Pre‑trial Memo, 1981 (Box 55, Folder 7)
  - Bar Complaint, 1982 (Box 55, Folder 8)
  - Trial Memos (Legal Issues), 1981 (Box 55, Folder 9)
  - Robert Wall, 1981 (Box 55, Folder 10)
  - Oral Arguments, 1981 (Box 55, Folder 11)
  - Material for Research‑Hobson Appeal, 1981-1983 (Box 55, Folder 12)
  - Jury Instructions and Special Verdict Form‑‑Parties Submissions, 1983 (Box 55, Folder 13)
  - Misc. Papers, 1981-1984 (Box 55, Folder 14)
  - Court Transcript (Vol. I), 1983 (Box 56, Folder 1)
  - Court Transcript (Vol. II), 1983 (Box 57, Folder 1)
  - Court Transcript (Vol. III), 1978 (Box 58, Folder 1)
  - Court Transcript (Vol. IV) Exhibitions, 1968 (Box 59, Folder 1)
  - Tina Hobson v. Wilson, 1981 (Box 59, Folder 2)
  - Motions by Defendants (Vol. 12), September‑October 1981 (Box 60, Folder 1)
  - Motions by Plaintiffs (Vol. 13), October‑November 1981 (Box 60, Folder 2)
  - Exhibits to Plaintiffs Pre‑Trial Brief Vol. 13A, 1981 (Box 60, Folder 3)
  - Hobson Pleading Vol. 14, October 29‑November 1981 (Box 61, Folder 1)
  - Hobson Pleading Vol. 15, November 1981 (Box 61, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous court Motions, Undated (Box 61, Folder 3)
- Series 15: University Teacher, 1968-1975
  The series contains correspondence, course outlines, roll books, and student papers from the course "Social Problems and the Law" which Hobson taught at American University and the Antioch Law School. Student papers are restricted.
  - Correspondence, Undated (Box 62, Folder 1)
  - Course Outlines, Undated (Box 62, Folder 2)
  - Roll Books, Undated (Box 62, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Papers, Undated (Box 62, Folder 4)
  - Student papers (restricted), Undated (Box 63, Folder 1)
  - Student papers (restricted), Undated (Box 64, Folder 1)
  - Student papers (restricted), Undated (Box 65, Folder 1)
  - Student papers (restricted), Undated (Box 66, Folder 1)